Amir Tabatabaei

tabatabaii.amir@outlook.com • (552) 303-6246 • Istanbul, Turkey

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

 A highly self-driven, motivated and competent frontend web developer. I am keen to be challenged to expand my horizons and further improve my Engineering skills. I actively follow my passion in life to use my technical know-how to develop with more than four years of related experiences to impact other people and organizations directly.

SKILLS

HTML • CSS/SASS/SCSS • Bootstrap • Tailwind • JavaScript • ES6 • React.js • Next.js

- Redux(Persist) Responsive web Design Cross-browser compatibility Mobile First Css
- React Folder Structure Single Page Application Development Rest Full API Webpack
 - i18n UX & UI Design Site Troubleshooting GitHub Agile / Scrum Firebase Photoshop Zeplin Sketch

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

 Front-end Web Developer (Uniq Design Factory- ISTANBUL) Jan 2020 – Sep 2021

The company is Advertising company in Istanbul.

I used HTML5, CSS3 or SCSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript (ES6), Rest Full API, React, Redux(persist) and another open source library to development the website such as Material-UI, Ant-Design and also I used Google Analytics for analyze web pages and Google Search Console and so on.

- Main Achievements: I got challenged with new problem-solving issues due to frequently changing the scenario. I working by Sketch or Zeplin to get projects and create a website and also I experienced working remotely with our teammate for first time because of Covid-19 epidemi.
- Front-end Web Developer (WEBMIN - TABRIZ)

Apr 2018 – Dec 2019

The company was web development company in Tabriz.

Design, build, or maintain web sites, using authoring or scripting languages, content creation tools and management tools.

I Developed web site, page templates that meet project goals, user needs, or industry standards. In team, I used HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap4, JavaScript, Rest API, React, Redux and another open source library to development the website or create a psychology questions web application and games, or e-commerce website.

- Main Achievements: Considering that my corporation with Webmin is temporary before
 moving out from Iran, But I enjoyed from learning the new technology of Front-end web
 development and I decided to continue learning.
- Front-end web developer (MAHAN – TABRIZ)

Oct 2016 - Feb 2018

The company was web development company in Tabriz.

Designing, developing, delivering and implementing web applications for clients and assisting in the development and maintenance of company web applications, with bootstrap library, css3 and JavaScript. Designing advertise banner or best resolution carousel images with Photoshop, and supporting customers website for one year.

Main Achievements: I learned how to manage projects that have deadlines. Immense
myself with the troubleshooting of bootstrap and CSS made websites

 System / Network Administrator (POWDER METALLURGY – TABRIZ) Oct 2015 - Oct 2016

Factory was the only manufacturer of friction plates in various sizes in Tabriz.

I was part-time Network/System administrator in the factory.

I set the server room in the factory and setup DHCP Server and Active Directory and other server program and I managed all users in Active Directory in Windows Server 2012 and also I fixed all off Computers/Network technical problem in the factory.

 System / Network Administrator (IMEN SYSTEM – TABRIZ) Mar 2013 - Aug 2016

The company was hardware and software company in Tabriz.

Maintained and administered computer networks and related computing environments including computer hardware, systems software, applications software, and all configurations. Configured local area network (LAN) switch or related equipment. Diagnosed, troubleshooted, and resolved hardware or other network and system problems, and replaced defective components when necessary. Designed, configured, and test computer hardware, networking software and operating system software.

• Main Achievements: I prepared to get Microsoft Certificate in Windows Server 2012 & 2016

EDUCATION

• TABRIZ UNIVERSITY

2013 - 2015

Master of Computer Science

• TABRIZ AZAD UNIVERSITY Bachelor of Computer Science

2009 - 2012

CERTIFICATE

Microsoft® Certified Solutions Associate: Windows Server 2012

June 2019

Microsoft® Certified Solutions Associate: Windows Server 2016

June 2019

Microsoft® Certified Solutions Associate: Core Infrastructure

June 2019

Credential URL: https://mcp.microsoft.com/Anonymous/Transcript/Validate

ID: 1234089 • Access Code: 5523036246

LANGUAGES

- Azerbaycani (Native or Bilingual Proficiency)
- English (Professional Working Proficiency)
- Turkish (Professional Working Proficiency)
- Persian (Native or Bilingual Proficiency)

INTERESTS

Learning new technology such as Vue or Angular, Mobile Applications (React Native / Flutter)

HOBBIES

Listening music • Reading Books • Photographing • Walking • Cooking • Camping